<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk.atom"/>
  <title>Beantown Bedding - BeansTalk Blog</title>
  <updated>2021-07-01T14:46:27-04:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/8-eco-friendly-hospitality-tips</id>
    <published>2021-07-01T14:46:27-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-07-02T12:37:47-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/8-eco-friendly-hospitality-tips"/>
    <title>E-Book: 8 Eco-Friendly Hospitality Tips</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<br><br>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://mcusercontent.com/79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26/files/edcc3de8-45f9-037d-4263-3dce359b0a66/8_Eco_Friendly_Hospitality_Tips.pdf" target="_blank" title="E-Book: 8 Eco-Friendly Hospitality Tips" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/8_Eco-Friendly_Hospitality_Tips_600x600.jpg?v=1625161833" alt="Eco-Friendly Hospitality Tips"></a></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">
<br><hr>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em><br>Take your hospitality business to a whole new level of sustainability this year with our latest list of eco-friendly tips. Our 8 Eco-Friendly Hospitality Tips are designed to help you reduce costs, save money and attract more guests. Go green today!<br></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">1. Upgrade Cleaning Supplies</span></strong></h3>
</div>
<p>Replace traditional cleaning supplies with all-natural, organic products. Plant-based products are just as effective as non-organic products but are kinder on your health, your guests and the environment. You'll also provide a better stay for guests with asthma or allergies.</p>
<br>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">2. Use Refillable Containers</span></strong></h3>
<p>Instead of using small plastic bottles, provide toiletries in reusable, refillable containers. You may also consider outfitting bathrooms with wall-mounted shampoos, conditioners and soap to further reduce waste. Organic soaps and toiletries will also help to provide a more eco-friendly environment for your guests. <em> </em></p>
<br>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">3. Go Paperless</span></strong></h3>
<p>Replace complimentary print newspapers with online, digital subscriptions. Studies have shown that the average person in the U.S. uses more than 700 pounds of paper per year—more than anywhere else in the world. Going digital can significantly reduce paper waste for your business. <em> </em></p>
<p> </p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">4. Make Recycling Easy</span></strong></h3>
<p>Place a recycling bin in each guest room alongside a full list of items that can be recycled. If you cater to business travelers, add another recycling bin next to all desks to make it even easier to recycle paper. <em> </em></p>
<p> </p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">5. Stock Up on Laundry-Free Linens®</span></strong></h3>
<p>No list of eco-friendly hospitality tips would be complete without Beantown Bedding®'s Laundry-Free Linens®. A first in sustainable disposables, these plant-based linens are chemical-free, dye-free and 100% compostable (and with no need to launder, they save on water, energy and carbon emissions). You'll also ensure guests that their sheets are clean and new, just for them. <em> </em></p>
<p> </p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">6. Consider Composting</span></strong></h3>
<p>NComposting diverts waste away from landfills and converts it into rich soil that can be used for gardening, landscaping and house plants. It also saves water, reduces greenhouse gasses and minimizes your overall impact on the environment. (A bonus tip? Beantown Bedding's Laundry-Free Linens are completely compostable!) <em> </em></p>
<p> </p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">7.<span> Donate Unused Food &amp; Beverages</span></span></strong></h3>
<p>Commit to reducing food waste by finding a local charity that will accept donations of unused food and beverages. List this partnership on menus, in welcome packages and on your website to make guests aware of your goals. </p>
<p> </p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">8.<span> Get Your Guests Involved</span></span></strong></h3>
<p>Include a reusable room card in each bedroom listing the environmental benefits of limiting laundry (like saving water and reducing your carbon footprint). Put similar cards in bathrooms to let guests know that only towels left on the floor will be washed. Getting guests involved in your eco-friendly efforts can significantly reduce your energy costs and add to your bottom line.</p>
<br>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/laundry-free-linens-collection" title="Shop"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/shop-now_a9444036-7ebc-4667-b8fc-4422e9f4c245_240x240.png?v=1606874075" alt="Shop Now" style="margin-right: 40.3333px; margin-left: 40.3333px; float: none;"></a></div>
<a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/wholesale-orders" title="Order Wholesale"> </a>
<p> </p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/travel-disposable-bedding</id>
    <published>2021-05-01T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2021-05-20T12:35:33-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/travel-disposable-bedding"/>
    <title>&quot;Beantown will be by my side during my upcoming European and domestic travel adventures.”</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Travel-Testimonial_1024x1024.png?v=1621527438" alt="Travel Review" width="1024x1024" height="1024x1024" style="margin-top: 50px; float: none;"><br><hr>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em><br>Beantown Bedding's eco-disposable bed sheets get some rave reviews from our customers and we just can't help but share some of our favorites!<br></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em></em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">A Full Post on Why This is Epic</span></strong></h3>
</div>
<p>"I came across Beantown Bedding on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l71bd_fRvfo" target="_blank" title="The View" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>The View</em> talk show</a>. Whoopi Goldberg featured her favorite retail goods and this business was one of the brands mentioned. Normally I pay the segment no mind but my ears perked up when it came to the BIODEGRADABLE bed linens (DISPOSABLE BEDDING) that you can take with you to hotels, college dorms, sleepovers, friend's houses, cheap motels and anywhere else a pissy mattress is found! Seriously, do I even need to write a full post on why this is epic? </p>
<br>
<p>The traveler in me has spent more times grossed out than not when it comes to my sleeping arrangements. I recently stayed at a 3-star hotel with good reviews in Northern California and felt the essence of mid-priced hooker glaze on my skin when I came in contact with the bed linen. I needed 3 baths, a disinfectant treatment, full body massage, and a shock therapy session just to eliminate both the bad memories and residues from the hotel-issued linens. This was a missed opportunity for disposable bedding to come in and save my life.</p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">Beantown Will Be By My Side</span></strong></h3>
<p>Like seriously someone is dropping the ball here. Airline companies need to hand out complimentary Beantown disposable bedding with purchase of airfare... All my phobias have collectively formed a sigh of relief. Please believe when I say that Beantown will be by my side during my upcoming European and domestic travel adventures.” </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>— <a href="https://kittybradshaw.com/" target="_blank" title="Travel Blogger" rel="noopener noreferrer">Kitty Bradshaw, Travel Blogger</a></em><br><em> </em></p><br>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/testimonials" title="Reviews of Beantown Bedding"><strong>Read More Beantown Bedding Reviews</strong></a></p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/laundry-free-linens-collection" title="Shop"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/shop-now_a9444036-7ebc-4667-b8fc-4422e9f4c245_240x240.png?v=1606874075" alt="Shop Now" style="margin-right: 40.3333px; margin-left: 40.3333px; float: none;"></a></div>
<a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/wholesale-orders" title="Order Wholesale"> </a>
<p> </p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/dirty-sheets-quarantine-housing</id>
    <published>2021-02-12T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-12T20:01:13-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/dirty-sheets-quarantine-housing"/>
    <title>Dirty Sheets and No Towels: What Quarantine Housing is Really Like</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Linens-Quarantine-Housing_1024x1024.png?v=1613176866" alt="Linens for Quarantine Housing" width="1024x1024" height="1024x1024" style="margin-top: 50px; float: none;"><br><hr>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Throughout the <a href="https://mailchi.mp/beantownbedding.com/covid-guide-for-campus-community" target="_blank" title="COVID-19 Guide" rel="noopener noreferrer">COVID-19 pandemic</a>, many college students have experienced what it's like to live in Quarantine Housing—housing reserved specifically for students who feel sick or have been in close contact with a COVID-19 positive individual. While some colleges are providing the essentials, like <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/laundry-free-linens-collection" title="bed sheets for quarantine housing">bed sheets, linens and towels for Quarantine Housing</a>, many students are still finding the amenities lacking<meta charset="utf-8">
<span>—</span>and the overall experience stressful. Here's what Quarantine Housing is <em>really</em> like according to three college students who've been there.</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">Stressful and Exhausting</span></strong></h3>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<p><em>"The entire process was difficult, confusing, and a downright bummer from start to finish. Although my experience was far from ideal, I hope I can better prepare others who could soon be in the same boat.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Inside the room, I found a bed with two stained top sheets and a rough, old blanket. The floor had stains all over it and one visibly wet and sticky mark in the middle of the carpet that I’m still actively avoiding. </em><em>...I double-layered the top sheets over the mattress and thankfully brought a blanket of my own and my own towel. These comforts have meant the most throughout this extended stay."</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Read more at <a href="https://onwardstate.com/2020/09/07/dirty-sheets-boxed-meals-my-penn-state-quarantine-experience/" target="_blank" title="quarantine housing" rel="noopener noreferrer">Onward State</a>.</p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<div style="text-align: left;">
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">10 Days Without a Pillow</span></strong></h3>
</div>
<p><em>"They provided us with bedding, but it’s not nice at all. They don’t really give us blankets, they give us those thin sheets to put over the bed. I recommend people going to wellness housing bring a pillow and a blanket, because they don’t give you either. They told me to bring a pillow, but my roommate who tested positive did not bring one, so she’s going to be here for 10 days without a pillow. They didn’t provide us with any towels and they didn’t advise us to bring them. Since my other two roommates came later, we asked them to drop stuff off in front of our door for us.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>My advice for anyone who has to move into wellness housing is to take your time to pack, because it can be super overwhelming. <a href="https://mcusercontent.com/79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26/files/72a291fd-ba25-4388-8df2-e9c78d9dae69/BB__Go_Bag_Packing_List.pdf" target="_blank" title="Go Bag Packing List" rel="noopener noreferrer">Make a list of what you should bring</a>. Bring comfy clothes, comfy bedding, pillows, towels, anything you need for the shower... Don’t be afraid to pack too much. You’re going to be here for 14 days and you can’t go back."</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: right;">Read more at <a href="https://huntnewsnu.com/63071/campus/when-your-roommate-tests-positive-life-in-northeasterns-quarantine-housing/" target="_blank" title="quarantine housing" rel="noopener noreferrer">Huntington News</a>. </p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;"></span></strong></h3>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">Nerve-Wracking and Kind of Scary</span></strong></h3>
<p><em>"Dust everywhere. On the bed and desks and everything... The counters looked like they hadn’t been wiped down. The toilet was running from the person who was just in there before me. Their linens were on the ground. I felt like, if I didn’t have COVID before, I’d get it now by staying here. It was nerve-racking and kind of scary.”</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><span>Read more at </span><a href="https://richmond.com/special-report/coronavirus/roommates-mistakenly-sent-to-vcu-isolation-dorm-say-its-a-nerve-racking-experience/article_c1ee6f53-726c-5e22-b8ef-2a69d314ddf7.html" target="_blank" title="quarantine housing" rel="noopener noreferrer">Richmond Times Dispatch</a><span>.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Shop Beantown Bedding's <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/laundry-free-linens-collection" title="sheets and towels for quarantine housing">Compostable Bed Sheets and Towels</a> for Quarantine Housing</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> </p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/laundry-free-linens-collection" title="Shop"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/shop-now_a9444036-7ebc-4667-b8fc-4422e9f4c245_240x240.png?v=1606874075" alt="Shop Now" style="margin-right: 40.3333px; margin-left: 40.3333px; float: none;"></a></div>
<a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/wholesale-orders" title="Order Wholesale"> </a>
<p> </p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/there-are-so-many-reasons-these-sheets-are-ideal</id>
    <published>2021-02-10T13:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-02-11T13:09:48-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/there-are-so-many-reasons-these-sheets-are-ideal"/>
    <title>&quot;There are so many reasons these sheets are ideal...&quot;</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/disposable-sheets-review_1024x1024.png?v=1613065466" alt="Disposable Sheet Reviews" width="1024x1024" height="1024x1024" style="margin-top: 50px; float: none;"><br><hr>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"><em>During the COVID-19 pandemic, Beantown Bedding's eco-disposable sheets have been getting rave reviews from our customers, and we just couldn't help but share one of our most recent favorites:</em></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">PERFECT - Especially helpful during COVID-19!</span></strong></h3>
</div>
<p>"I’m very happy with my purchase! I was given a set of these sheets as a gift and just found them on Amazon. I read the reviews before buying them and I agree with the five-star reviews. One negative review stated these sheets are a disposable mattress pad - NOT TRUE! Yes, they are disposable but they go into the compost pile and not my garbage can. I did some research and read the fabric is naturally antimicrobial. During this crisis with COVID-19, they’re worth every penny.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Because of the pandemic, I have been very reluctant to do my laundry in a laundromat. I’ve been hand washing my clothes but that doesn’t work with sheets! Laundromats aren’t cheap either! The last time I washed and dried my sheets there, it cost $8. I’ve used the set I was given for over three weeks and am quite impressed with their durability. They’re NOT like disposable linens in a hospital (surgical gowns, pillow cases, etc.) and they’re very soft - softer than my regular sheets.</p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">Cool and Comfortable All Night</span></strong></h3>
<p>I was concerned they might make me too hot because the feeling of them seemed a bit like flannel sheets. These sheets did not make me too hot at all and I felt cool and comfortable all night. After trying these I’ve decided to buy several sets of them for travel. I typically travel often and will be traveling again after it’s safe and the stay home orders are lifted. When I’ve stayed with family or friends, I’ve had trouble with having allergic reactions to the laundry soap the host has used. I can put these right on top of the sheets already on the bed when staying with family/friends and take them with me when I leave.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I also won’t have to worry if I get a makeup smudge or skincare product on the pillowcase - that happened to me in the past. Once while I was staying in the guest room of a friend, I thought I had removed all of my makeup. When I awoke the next morning there were several mascara smudges on the pillowcase that was part of a custom made bedding set (comforter, shams, dust ruffle and sheets) and I couldn’t wash it out. It was very embarrassing!</p>
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">Less Laundry Would Have Helped A Lot</span></strong></h3>
<p>I’m going to take them when I stay in hotels too. I was in a 4-star hotel a few years ago and the cleaning staff was cleaning several rooms near mine. The occupants of those rooms had checked out so every room needed the bedding changed. One of the hotel’s cleaning staff put a clean set of sheets for each room next to the door ON THE FLOOR. Of course, I reported it to the manager but it made me think of how many things like that go on without guest’s knowledge. Now, more than ever, I’ll take whatever safety measures I can to guard against exposure to the COVID-19 virus and all other germs.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I wish I had known about these sheets when I was living in California during the severe drought. Less laundry would have helped a lot especially when my kids were still living at home. There are so many reasons these sheets are ideal for me and I highly recommend them!"</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/testimonials" title="Reviews of Beantown Bedding"><strong>Read More Beantown Bedding Reviews</strong></a></p>
<br>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/laundry-free-linens-collection" title="Shop"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/shop-now_a9444036-7ebc-4667-b8fc-4422e9f4c245_240x240.png?v=1606874075" alt="Shop Now" style="margin-right: 40.3333px; margin-left: 40.3333px; float: none;"></a></div>
<a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/wholesale-orders" title="Order Wholesale"> </a>
<p> </p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/beantown-beddings-high-five-program-rev-up-revenue-in-the-off-season</id>
    <published>2020-12-10T16:04:22-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-16T12:40:32-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/beantown-beddings-high-five-program-rev-up-revenue-in-the-off-season"/>
    <title>High Five: A New Way to Earn Revenue for University Housing &amp; Events</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<br>Looking for a new way to earn revenue for <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/conferences-events" title="Housing &amp; Events">University Housing or Events</a>? Offer up Laundry-Free Linens<span>®</span>! With Beantown Bedding's High-Five Program, you can give your guests a deep discount on Laundry-Free Linens®<span> while earning revenue for your department. </span>Here's how it works:</div>
<br>
<p><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/BB__High_Five_Program_1024x1024.png?v=1607635404" alt="Earn Revenue" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></span></p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><span>Interested in learning more? Email <a href="mailto:ellsie@beantownbedding.com?subject=High%20Five%20Program">ellsie@beantownbedding.com</a>. </span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/wholesale-orders" title="Order Wholesale"><span><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/HC-CTA_480x480.png?v=1607048709" alt=""></span></a></p>
<br><br>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/case-study-how-3-hospitals-are-using-laundry-free-linens</id>
    <published>2020-12-02T15:19:40-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-12-04T14:00:01-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/case-study-how-3-hospitals-are-using-laundry-free-linens"/>
    <title>Case Study: Why Hospitals Are Asking For Laundry-Free Linens®</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/hospital-case-studies_1024x1024.png?v=1607046976" alt="Laundry-Free Linens" width="1024x1024" height="1024x1024" style="margin-top: 40px; float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<hr>
<p> </p>
<p>In a <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare" title="Healthcare">healthcare setting</a>, Laundry-Free Linens® are fast and effective—not to mention incredibly clean and comfortable. Here's a quick look at how a number of hospitals are using Laundry-Free Linens® in the field. From <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare">surge capacity to infection control</a>, these eco-disposable bed sheets are helping healthcare professionals save time and guarantee clean no matter the circumstances.</p>
<h3><span style="color: #4b9b28;"><strong>〉 Surge Capacity and Field Hospitals</strong></span></h3>
<p>At the start of COVID-19, one of the largest hospital systems on the east coast significantly increased its monthly order of Laundry-Free Linens®. This was to prepare for surge capacity which meant accommodating up to 25 percent more patients than usual. Due to warehousing locations on both the east and west coasts, Beantown Bedding was able to quickly accommodate this request, allowing one of the country's largest healthcare providers to begin using Laundry-Free Linens® almost immediately in its emergency rooms. This <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/sustainability#calculator">eliminated laundry for approximately 300 to 500 beds</a> each day, which freed up resources and reduced the burden on staff during a critical time. Because Laundry-Free Linens® are used by just a single patient and are composted rather than laundered, the linens also reduced the risk of cross contamination. As the pandemic progressed, Laundry-Free Linens® were further deployed in field hospitals where individually wrapped sets allowed staff to "grab 'n go" linens while managing an unprecedented surge in hospitalizations.</p>
<h3><span style="color: #4b9b28;"><strong>〉 Infection Control</strong></span></h3>
<p>Laundry-Free Linens® are also playing an important role within a world-renowned Bone Marrow and Stem Cell Transplant program. Since Laundry-Free Linens® are individually wrapped and guaranteed clean, they were an easy choice for <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/did-you-know-hospital-bed-linens-could-be-a-source-of-infection-even-after-being-washed">hospital administrators focused on infection control</a>. According to one staff member: “The bone marrow transplant families were absolutely thrilled [with the linens] because they have to be so careful about infection and we do not trust traditional sheets for these patients.” Combining comfort and cleanliness, Laundry-Free Linens® were deployed in both the hospital's maternity ward and bone marrow transplant program with great success. The linens' eco-disposable nature mean sheets are always clean and new, which provides peace of mind for patients and ease of use for caregivers. As a compostable product, they also help to offset the carbon emissions, electricity and water usage of commercial laundering.</p>
<h3><span style="color: #4b9b28;"><strong>〉 Staff Overnights</strong></span></h3>
<p>One New England hospital goes laundry-free in order to better prepare for emergencies. Many staff members will stay overnight during emergencies and require clean linens themselves. This previously <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare">led to shortages of sheets</a>, forcing staff to conserve linens and keep an even closer eye on supplies. The hospital also had concerns about its regular linen provider<span>—</span>during a previous storm its provider was unable to make deliveries, leaving the hospital at risk of running out of clean sheets. Laundry-Free Linens® have proved the perfect solution. The individually wrapped sets are not only convenient for staff overnights, but also help to regulate linen levels and ensure that a clean supply of linen is always on hand.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Laundry-Free Linens®—the best disposable sheets for healthcare.</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> </p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/wholesale-orders"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/HC-CTA_480x480.png?v=1607048709" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></a></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"> </p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/field-hospitals-for-covid-19-surge-dorms-conference-centers-and-camps-offer-hospitals-more-beds</id>
    <published>2020-03-30T16:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-10-08T15:35:45-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/field-hospitals-for-covid-19-surge-dorms-conference-centers-and-camps-offer-hospitals-more-beds"/>
    <title>Field Hospitals for COVID-19 Surge: Dorms, Conference Centers and Camps</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>News for those working "feverishly" to build capacity for the surge in Coronavirus patients.  Conference centers, camps and university dorms are turning into makeshift hospitals to provide extra beds for the crisis.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/field-hospitals-for-covid-19-surge-dorms-conference-centers-and-camps-offer-hospitals-more-beds">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong> </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/field_hospitals_needs_linens_large.jpg?v=1585601233" alt=""><br>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Setting Up Field Hospitals </strong></p>
<br>
<p>There's no shortage of COVID-19 news, but here's a bite-sized portion that's relevant to those working "feverishly" to build capacity for the surge in Coronavirus patients.  For more news, check out our <a href="https://mailchi.mp/beantownbedding.com/updates" target="_blank" title="covid19 updates" rel="noopener noreferrer">COVID-19 Updates page</a>.</p>
<div class="mcnCaptionBlock">
<div class="mcnCaptionBlockInner">
<div class="mcnCaptionColumn">
<div>
<div class="mcnTextContent">
<p><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=7aa02df501" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Hospitals are being set up on soccer fields, in state park cabins, and converted convention centers</a><br>Washington Post<br><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=2739f9d44f" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">How South Korea solved its hospital bed shortage</a> <em>(Hint: dorms)</em><br>Wall Street Journal<br><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=702c20e1d6" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NY Presbyterian casts wide net in search of equipment</a> (email: masks@nyp.org)<br>NY Post<br><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=c933bcb45b" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Deluge of cases begins hitting hospitals</a><br>NY Times<br><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=4c2a241d40" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NY...may need 140,000 hospital beds, Cuomo warns</a><br>Fox News<br><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=1e0faf8056" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">When is LA County Hospitals' tipping point?</a><br>LA Times<br><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=a5c7f45835" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Florida deploys 3 field hospitals</a><br>WSVN Miami<br><br><a href="https://mc.us3.list-manage.com/pages/track/click?u=79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26&amp;id=5f2894f3fe" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">NJ scrambles to expand hospital capacity before expected coronavirus surge</a><br>Wall Street Journal</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="mcnDividerBlock">
<div class="mcnDividerBlockInner"></div>
</div>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/linens-and-coronavirus-how-5-healthcare-communities-are-preparing</id>
    <published>2020-03-05T16:25:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-21T20:52:43-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/linens-and-coronavirus-how-5-healthcare-communities-are-preparing"/>
    <title>It&apos;s War.  How 5 Healthcare Communities are Preparing for Coronavirus</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p><strong></strong>Across the U.S., hospital administrators, support services personnel, and emergency management officials are fighting a battle they're trained to fight. Coronavirus, or COVID-19, is the latest infectious disease enemy, but like any wartime effort, supplies, surges and shortages are making it a challenge.</p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/linens-and-coronavirus-how-5-healthcare-communities-are-preparing">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><img alt="Coronavirus Best Practices" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/covid_1024x1024.jpg?v=1584633995" style="display: block; margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<br>
<p><strong>It's War. </strong></p>
<br>
<p>Across the U.S., hospital administrators, support services personnel, and emergency management officials are fighting a battle they're trained to fight. Coronavirus, or COVID-19, is the latest infectious disease enemy, but like any wartime effort, supplies, surges and shortages are making it a challenge. </p>
<p> </p>
<p>In the spotlight are five healthcare communities and how they're preparing. From low-tech best practices to high-tech robots, infection control measures often include special protocols for dealing with bed linen. At some of America's top hospitals, a new kind of linen from <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare" target="_blank" title="new kind of disposable hospital linen for infection control" rel="noopener noreferrer">Beantown Bedding</a> is being deployed: eco-disposable and laundry-free. </p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>In the Spotlight:</strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>New York, </em><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="https://brooklyneagle.com/articles/2020/02/17/coronavirus-is-new-york-city-prepared-to-deal-with-thousands-of-cases/" target="_blank" title="Surge capacity at hospitals" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #0000ff;">Surge Capacity</a></span>:<em> "Hospitals have to muster extra staff, stockpile protective gear, equipment..and arrange myriad details — like...extra sheets."</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>California</em>, <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/02/26/robotic-medicine-may-be-the-weapon-needed-to-combat-the-coronavirus.html" target="_blank" title="Using robotic medicine to combat Coronavirus" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #0000ff;">Employing Robots</a></span>: <em>"At Stanford Health...robots are bringing supplies and <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/business/article/Need-hospital-linens-At-new-Stanford-Hospital-14871666.php" title="Need hospital linens? At Stanford call the robot." target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #0000ff;">linens</a></span> to the ward."</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Massachusetts, </em><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/top-hospital-braces-coronavirus-pandemic-secret-warehouse-full-emergency-supplies-n1149976" target="_blank" title="Hospital warehouse for infectious disease outbreak" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #0000ff;">A Secret Warehouse</a></span>:<em> "Outside Boston sits a secret warehouse filled with hundreds of boxes labeled 'pandemic product.'"</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>North Carolina</em>, <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="https://www.northcarolinahealthnews.org/2020/03/04/how-do-hospitals-prepare-for-an-outbreak-the-first-place-to-look-in-is-in-their-warehouse/" target="_blank" title="Mobile medical units for Coronavirus outbreak" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #0000ff;">Mobile Medical Units</a></span>: <em>"Supplies also included other such mundane items as folding chairs and tables, disposable pillows, linens, air mattresses and cots."</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><em>Michigan</em>, <span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="https://www.ourmidland.com/news/article/Midland-County-prepares-for-Coronavirus-15102722.php#photo-19074849" target="_blank" title="Healthcare community prepares for Coronavirus" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #0000ff;">Healthcare Community Prepares for Coronavirus</a></span>: <em>"Following comprehensive procedures for disinfecting patient rooms and removing/disposing of linens and cubicle curtains."</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><strong>Other Resources:</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><span style="color: #0000ff;"><a href="https://www.who.int/publications-detail/infection-prevention-and-control-during-health-care-when-novel-coronavirus-(ncov)-infection-is-suspected-20200125" target="_blank" title="WHO: Infection Prevention and control during health care...Coronavirus" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #0000ff;">WHO (World Health Organization): Infection Prevention and control during health care when novel coronavirus (nCoV) infection is suspected</a></span>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/preview/mmwrhtml/rr5210a1.htm" title="CDC Guidelines for Environmental Infection Control in Healthcare Facilities (Bedding)" style="color: #0000ff;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">CDC (Centers for Disease Control and Prevention): Guidelines for Environmental Infection Control in Healthcare Facilities (see Laundry and Bedding)</a></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><em>Learn more about eco-disposable Laundry-Free Linens for <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare">healthcare</a> and <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/emergency-planning">emergency management</a>.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/did-you-know-hospital-bed-linens-could-be-a-source-of-infection-even-after-being-washed</id>
    <published>2020-03-01T12:30:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-21T20:50:31-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/did-you-know-hospital-bed-linens-could-be-a-source-of-infection-even-after-being-washed"/>
    <title>Did You Know? Hospital Bed Linens Could be a Source of Infection Even After Being Washed</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Healthcare-Linens_1024x1024.png?v=1565281378" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p>A new study published in the <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/infection-control-and-hospital-epidemiology/listing?q=linens&amp;_csrf=OFbn04YV-7mBnN7CMT1dEiOM2ulD7DnaVWSk&amp;searchWithinIds=95EF576C9780A64242FCC544A02D3A60" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #38761d;">Infection Control &amp; Hospital Epidemiology journal</a></span> will make you even more nervous about your next hospital stay. The recent <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.modernhealthcare.com/article/20181016/NEWS/181019914/hospital-bed-linens-could-be-source-of-c-difficile-outbreaks" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #38761d;">study cited in Modern Healthcare</a></span> suggests that hospital bed linens could be a source of C. difficile outbreaks and infection even after the sheets have been washed.</p>
<p><br> "The study looked at inoculated swatches of cotton sheets with C. difficile that were then laundered with sterile uncontaminated pieces of fabric to measure the levels of contamination before and after washing.</p>
<p><br> Researchers washed naturally contaminated bed linens in a commercial washer with industrial detergent at 167 degrees Fahrenheit for eight minutes. The study found the laundering process reduced C. difficile spore counts by only 40%, failing to meet microbiological standards for containing no disease-causing bacteria."</p>
<p><br> According to Modern Healthcare, C. difficile is a common infection acquired in healthcare settings that <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.cdc.gov/media/releases/2015/p0225-clostridium-difficile.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" style="color: #38761d;">costs hospitals nearly $5 billion a year</a></span> in excess healthcare costs.</p>
<p><br> Experts warned that <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare" style="color: #38761d;">hospitals using commercial washers</a></span> to decontaminate sheets with C. difficile could also be spreading the bacteria when sheets are washed, reused and mixed in with uncontaminated sheets. A similar study in 2016 that investigated soiled linens in Seattle found that linens that tested positive for C. difficile had even contaminated areas within the facility where the linens were stored.</p>
<p><br> While some experts caution that the risk remains small, the ability of certain bacteria to survive on hospital bed linens even after being washed increases the possibility of acquiring infection through bed linens.</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h3 style="text-align: center;"><span style="color: #38761d;"><strong><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare" style="color: #38761d;">Learn More About Beantown Bedding for Healthcare</a></strong> </span></h3>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/whats-it-like-to-launch-a-startup</id>
    <published>2020-02-03T21:16:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-05-21T21:17:21-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/whats-it-like-to-launch-a-startup"/>
    <title>What&apos;s it Like to Launch a Startup?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Q&amp;A:  We asked Kirsten a few questions about her career path, what the start-up process was like and what advice she'd give to others who are considering starting their own business.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/whats-it-like-to-launch-a-startup">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><img alt="female founders and their startups" src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/South_Shore_Living_Kirsten_1.jpeg?v=1590109923" style="display: block; margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></strong></p>
<h1>Take the Leap</h1>
<p><em>(excerpt from interview with UH Alumni Organization)</em></p>
<p>Kirsten Lambert and her business partner Joan Ripple created <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Beantown Bedding</a>, an innovative bedding company specializing in Eco Disposable sheets that are 100% compostable and biodegradable.</p>
<br>
<p>We asked Kirsten a few questions about her career path, what the start-up process was like and what advice she'd give to others who are considering starting their own business.</p>
<br>
<p><strong>Tell us about your career path. Did you always envision that you’d be doing what you’re doing today?</strong></p>
<br>
<p>Not at all! Although I was always drawn to business, I never dreamed that I’d start my own. Prior to Beantown I had a 20+ year career in consumer research, first working on the supply side for large CPGs and later as a consultant. It was my role as a researcher and a mom that led to creating a business to solve a problem I discovered when sending my first child to college. My business partner Joan Ripple and I learned that our kids in college rarely took time to wash their sheets. Our answer was to come up with eco-disposable “laundry-free” sheets to keep them healthier and save them time in the laundry room. It turned out to be a disruptive solution for universities, camps and hospitals as well.</p>
<br>
<p><strong>What was the start-up process like?</strong></p>
<br>
<p>I’ve never been skydiving, but imagine it’s similar. You can prepare, but then you have to jump. After a year of research, formulating a business plan, and establishing a supply chain, our launch was like hurling ourselves out of the plane. It felt out of control, exhilarating and pretty scary. USA Today put Beantown on the front page right out of the gate, which led to a wave of media attention and a steep learning curve. Then we were a part of the MassChallenge accelerator; much like college for startups. It was a game changer that fueled our vision and gave us tools and guidance to grow. Seven years in it’s still exciting, and a little less scary.</p>
<br>
<p><strong>What’s been the most rewarding aspect of entrepreneurship? The most challenging?</strong></p>
<br>
<p>Building something from nothing is extremely fulfilling. It’s been a journey of professional and personal growth, pushing me well out of my comfort zone. Learning new things every day keeps it interesting and makes us better. It’s proof that grit overcomes a lot of shortcomings.</p>
<br>
<p>One of the most difficult aspects of doing something new is staying focused on a single strategy in the face of so many enticing opportunities. Since we essentially created a new category, there were many different potential paths, and it’s risky to commit all resources to a single direction. Our B2B business grew quickly out of the B2C business and became the driving force. Vector is just as important as velocity.</p>
<br>
<p><strong>What’s one message you’d like to pass on to students considering starting a business?</strong></p>
<br>
<p>Fail until you don’t. One of the most true maxims I’ve heard is, “I never lose. I only win or learn.” Failure is redefined in hindsight when you can look back and see what was gained from an experience. Tenacity is an absolute necessity.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/case-study-see-how-south-shore-hospital-is-using-laundry-free-linens</id>
    <published>2020-01-15T17:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2021-08-11T11:22:32-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/case-study-see-how-south-shore-hospital-is-using-laundry-free-linens"/>
    <title>Case Study: Why Emergency Managers are Asking for Laundry-Free Linens®</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;">
<a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/emergency-planning" title="Emergency Planning"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Disposable-Sheets-Emergency_1024x1024.png?v=1607481710" alt="Emergency Planning" width="1024x1024" height="1024x1024" style="margin-top: 50px; float: none;"></a><hr>
</div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">According to the CDC, U.S. hospitals produce <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/sustainability#calculator" style="color: #38761d;">more than 5 billion pounds of laundry</a></span> each year—which makes managing emergency linens a never-ending task. South Shore Hospital, a provider of acute, outpatient, home health and hospice care, was one of the first facilities to address this challenge by using Beantown Bedding's innovative Laundry-Free Linens®. </div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">〉The Problem</span></strong></h3>
</div>
<p>After a steady increase in inpatient admissions, South Shore Hospital sought to better prepare for emergencies, which often led to shortages of beds, linens and transportation. Many staff members would have <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare" style="color: #38761d;">unexpected overnight stays during emergencies</a></span> and would require linens themselves, which meant conserving bed sheets and keeping a close eye on supplies. The hospital also had concerns about its regular linen provider; during a recent winter storm, the linen provider was unable to make deliveries and the hospital was at risk of running out of clean sheets.</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<h3><strong><span style="color: #4b9b28;">〉The Solution</span></strong></h3>
<p>South Shore Hospital turned to Beantown Bedding to accommodate its staff. Laundry-Free Linens® are incredibly soft, eco-disposable sheets that were the perfect solution for workers staying overnight. The <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/healthcare" style="color: #38761d;">grab 'n go sets are not only convenient</a></span> (no washing), there was also no guilt in discarding them as they are entirely compostable. Having Laundry-Free Linens® on hand also helped the hospital regulate linen levels and ensure that a sufficient supply of clean linen was always available. <br><br> Working with the <span style="color: #38761d;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/testimonials" style="color: #38761d;">Director of <span style="color: #4b9b28;">Environmental</span> Services</a></span> and Emergency Planning Manager, Beantown Bedding was able to deliver comfort, support and convenience to hospital staff members. And since Laundry-Free Linens® are biodegradable and hypoallergenic, they are also being considered as a potential solution for additional departments within the hospital. </p>
<br> <br> <meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Laundry-Free Linens®—the best disposable sheets for <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/emergency-planning" title="Emergency Planning">Emergency Planning</a>.</strong></p>
<br>
<p> </p>
<br>
<p><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/collections/wholesale-orders" title="Order Wholesale"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/HC-CTA_480x480.png?v=1607048709" alt="Order Wholesale" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></a></p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/compostable-bed-sheets-for-uva-orientations-helps-the-whole-campus-go-green</id>
    <published>2019-09-30T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-19T12:27:34-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/compostable-bed-sheets-for-uva-orientations-helps-the-whole-campus-go-green"/>
    <title>Compostable Bed Sheets For UVA Orientations Help Whole Campus Go Green</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span><span>Preparing for the school year to begin can be a drain on resources for colleges across the country, and not just economically. Setting up visiting days and orientations requires the preparation of large amounts of food, providing rooms for thousands of students, and cleaning up after every event.</span></span>
<p> </p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/compostable-bed-sheets-for-uva-orientations-helps-the-whole-campus-go-green">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Disposable-Sheets-Orientation_1024x1024.png?v=1565282030" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><em>A version of this <a href="https://www.greenmatters.com/community/2018/03/27/ZaJfVX/uva-green-orientation" style="color: #246ebe;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">article originally appeared on GreenMatters</a>, a site dedicated to interesting news and topics regarding sustainability.</em> <br><br> Preparing for the school year to begin can be a drain on resources for colleges across the country, and not just economically. Setting up visiting days and orientations requires the preparation of large amounts of food, providing rooms for thousands of students, and cleaning up after every event. All of this can take a real toll on the environment, which is why the University of Virginia (UVA) teams up with Beantown Bedding and <a href="https://www.blackbearcomposting.com/" style="color: #246ebe;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Black Bear Composting</a> to tackle one waste stream in particular: bedding. <br><br> During UVA visiting days, thousands of bedsheets are used by overnight students and guests for, at most, a few nights. But washing all of these sheets can have a <a href="https://www.nps.gov/articles/laundry.htm" style="color: #246ebe;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">significant impact on the environment</a>. A typical load of laundry uses approximately 30 to 40 gallons of water as well as a lot of energy to heat the water. On top of that, many laundry detergents are harmful to the environment, and each laundry cycle releases toxins into the environment that could have a <a href="https://home.howstuffworks.com/laundry-detergent4.htm" style="color: #246ebe;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">significant impact on climate change</a>. Since sheets are bulky, it also takes a large amount of energy to wash the thousands of sheet sets used by visiting students. <br><br> Instead of releasing this impact on the environment, UVA instead uses Laundry-Free Linens® for all of its freshman orientations. Beantown Bedding's sheets are completely eco-friendly throughout their lifecycle; made from responsibly-sourced eucalyptus, the sheets are USDA certified as 100 percent biobased, require no laundering, and biodegrade quickly with no toxic residues. The sheets return to nature in as little as two weeks. <br><br> The composting of UVA's sheets is facilitated by Black Bear Composting, an organics recycling company located in the Blue Ridge Mountains of Virginia. The company helps local businesses, organizations and residents <a href="https://www.epa.gov/recycle/reducing-waste-what-you-can-do" style="color: #246ebe;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">reduce their waste stream</a> by recycling organic materials—like food scraps, yard trimmings, and clean waste wood—into products for healthy soil. <br><br> After UVA orientation, Black Bear Composting picks up the sheets and composts them right alongside the food scraps from UVA's campus, eventually donating a portion of the rich compost back to UVA for use in its Community Garden. In other words, UVA is implementing full-circle composting for both environmental responsibility and campus beautification. <br><br> UVA joins a larger movement of colleges, universities and event venues turning to composting in order to reduce the waste produced by large events. UVA's use of Laundry-Free Linens® has even been <a href="https://www.compostingcouncil.org/page/ourcampuscomposts" style="color: #246ebe;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">recognized by the U.S. Composting Council</a> as an excellent example of full-cycle composting.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/beantown-bedding-for-business"><img alt="Shop Now" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/shop-now_compact.png?v=1573146878" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; float: none;"></a></p>
<p> </p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/college-students-need-to-hear-about-these-laundry-free-bed-sheets</id>
    <published>2019-06-05T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-19T12:27:45-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/college-students-need-to-hear-about-these-laundry-free-bed-sheets"/>
    <title>College Students Need to Hear All About These Laundry-Free Bed Sheets</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8"><span><span>The monthly ritual of stripping your bed to wash your sheets is over. No more wasting money on detergent. No more rolls of quarters for a machine dedicated only to your sheets. Beantown Bedding, a Boston company started by two moms who were sending their kids off to college </span></span><meta charset="utf-8"><span>and couldn't find disposable sheets.</span>
<p> </p><p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/college-students-need-to-hear-about-these-laundry-free-bed-sheets">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/College-Student-Sheets_1024x1024.png?v=1565283046" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><em>This article was written by Emily McKeon, Writer at FreshU, and originally appeared on the Fresh U website which focuses on the new experiences of freshmen in college.</em> <br><br> The monthly ritual of stripping your bed to wash your sheets is over. No more wasting money on detergent. No more rolls of quarters for a machine dedicated only to your sheets. Beantown Bedding, a Boston company started by two moms who were sending their kids off to college and couldn't find disposable sheets, has the solution for every college kid who does not have the time, or frankly, the money to wash sheets every month. <br><br> I was sent a Twin XL set which comes with a fitted sheet, flat sheet and pillowcase. The Full and Queen options additionally come with two pillowcases. Upon looking at what goes into this biodegradable product, I was surprised to find no cotton or silk listed. Usually, when one thinks of sheets, you think of the two aforementioned materials. I took this as meaning that they would maybe not be as soft as the cotton sheets I currently had on my bed. Boy, was I wrong. <br><br> The first of the set that I tested was the pillowcase. I slipped my pillow inside, rested my head on it, and was immediately taken aback by how soft and comfortable it felt. It was akin to laying on a cloud. My previous pillowcase was okay. It got the job done, but it was definitely not as soft as the Beantown Bedding pillowcase. <br><br> I then wrestled the fitted sheet on, as fitted sheets are almost always a pain in the neck to get onto any bed, and was again surprised by how soft it was. Okay, yes, it's a plus when the pillowcase is soft, but the fitted sheet too? Wow. <br><br> The flat sheet came next, and sure enough, it was as soft as an alpaca. I can now see what the rave is about Beantown Bedding. Not only are their products soft, but it is absolutely comfortable to move around in the bed. You don't get the slight tug from silk nor the scratchiness associated with cotton. A check in my books. <br><br> Thinking of traveling soon? Beantown Bedding is perfect for on-the-go traveling. The hypoallergenic, responsibly sourced sheets can fit into any luggage! The best part is you can sleep easy knowing that these sheets are compostable, helping to reduce your carbon footprint. <br><br> You can even sign up for a subscription service via Beantown Bedding's online shop, so you don't have to worry about re-purchasing every month. <br><br> The best part about this company is that every purchase helps the company to donate their products to Camp Sunshine. <br><br> Beantown Bedding is not only soft and comfortable, but great for the environment as well as your health. Save time, save quarters, go biodegradable! <br><br> <em>Disclaimer: This product was gifted, but all opinions are the writer's own.</em></p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/being-environmentally-friendly-has-perks-for-colleges-and-universities</id>
    <published>2019-05-25T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-19T12:28:40-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/being-environmentally-friendly-has-perks-for-colleges-and-universities"/>
    <title>Being Environmentally Friendly Has Perks for Colleges and Universities</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Environment-Friendly-Campus_6be1e941-e216-4702-bbfe-7d574e5f3114_1024x1024.png?v=1565282710" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p>Did you know? According to Crain's Business, being environmentally friendly—like planting trees around campus, replacing light bulbs, and composting food waste—has significant perks for colleges and universities that go far beyond the feel good factor: <br><br> <em>"Being environmentally friendly has potential perks for colleges and universities beyond the altruistic. For one, using less energy or sending less trash to landfills comes with measurable cost savings. For another, it's a way to differentiate an institution in a competitive marketpla</em>ce." <br><br> <strong>Cost Savings Are Significant</strong> <br><br> Among a number of initiatives identified, the article notes a recent Ohio university residence hall that cut waste costs in half by implementing a simple recycling program. Strides in solar and wind energy, along with on-campus farming, have also made significant impacts: <br><br> <em>"[Universities have] turned sustainability initiatives into an internal investment strategy...They used to be looked at as a cost from the campus budget. Now, there's an upfront cost, but the university knows it will recoup and reinvest the savings."</em></p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/heres-how-you-can-live-more-sustainably-on-campus</id>
    <published>2019-03-15T12:35:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-30T16:28:40-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/heres-how-you-can-live-more-sustainably-on-campus"/>
    <title>Here&apos;s How You Can Live More Sustainably on Campus</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Green-Campus_1024x1024.jpg?v=1565282416" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><em>This article originally appeared in The News Record, University of Cincinnati's independent, student-run newspaper.</em> <br><br> Recycling and eco-friendly living have grown popular in the U.S. over the past couple of decades. As scientific research about pollution rolls in, people have become more conscious about their choices, from biking to work to carrying a refillable bottle. <br><br> Living sustainably may seem like an unreachable goal for college students — especially those who live in dorms, where it often feels like every decision has already been made. <br><br> So, what can students do to decrease their carbon footprint? Check out the list below for some tips on how to live more eco-consciously. <br><br> <strong>Reconsider your method of transportation</strong> <br><br> If you want to live sustainably, be mindful about the transportation options you choose. Biking, walking and ride-sharing are all great ways to reduce your carbon footprint. The university even offers bike rentals for students through the Bike Kitchen, located at 101 W Daniels St. on the University of Cincinnati’s Uptown campus. <br><br> "We have a fleet of about 26 bikes that are free,” said Daniel Hart, sustainability coordinator at UC Sustainability. “It’s called the Bearcat Bike Share for students, staff, and faculty to check out [bikes] for up to a week.” <br><br> <strong>Reduce food waste</strong> <br><br> Composting is a great way to cut back on food waste. While UC does not give students the ability to compost their own waste, the university has implemented composting initiatives in several dining halls, including On the Green and Market Point. <br><br> Students can also reduce the amount of meat they consume. UC’s food courts offer plenty of meatless options, and there are even vegan options. <br><br> Outside of the dining halls, students should also consider where their food is coming from. Locally produced foods mean less energy spent in transportation, which in turn reduces your carbon footprint. <br><br> <strong>It’s all about the little things</strong> <br><br> “Every little thing helps when it comes to sustainability,” said Erin LeFever, assistant sustainability coordinator at UC Sustainability. “Things people can do on a daily basis, like drink coffee from a reusable mug, can make a difference. Students can cut out single-use plastic from their lives pretty easily by using a reusable water bottle, reusable bags and reusable coffee mugs.” <br><br> Looking for other simple ways to reduce energy consumption and plastic waste? Try these: <br><br></p>
<ol>
<ol>
<li>Whenever possible, take the stairs instead of the elevator</li>
<li>Bring reusable utensils when going out to eat — even if it’s just a reusable straw</li>
<li>Take shorter showers</li>
<li>If nobody else is in the dorm, turn off the lights when you leave</li>
</ol>
</ol>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/dealing-with-bedbugs-in-college</id>
    <published>2018-11-05T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-08T12:27:25-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/dealing-with-bedbugs-in-college"/>
    <title>Dealing with Bedbugs in College</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Bedbugs-College_1024x1024.png?v=1565281629" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><em>This article was written by Gwen Elise, Author at Student Caffe, and originally appeared on the Student Caffe Blog, a place to explore real topics relating to students. </em></p>
<p><br> When I was a college sophomore, an acquaintance of mine from the adjacent dorm building noticed nasty bites all over his body. He assumed that whatever he was going through was an isolated incident—spider bites, maybe—but what he didn’t know was that other residents in the building were also being bitten at night. By the time they banded together and figured out that bedbugs had moved into their dorm, the ruthless little creatures had taken over the top two floors of the building. The word got out, and soon everyone at school knew about the infestation. “Don’t go in there,” we nonresidents would whisper ominously to each other when we walked past the place. “That dorm has bedbugs.”</p>
<p><br> <strong>⚠️ Already dealing with bed bugs? Check out 6 Home Remedies to Get Rid of Bed Bugs </strong></p>
<p><br> Few outbreaks are feared more by college students than bedbugs. Not only are they keen to spread and difficult to treat, but bedbugs come with a social stigma. We think of them as indicators of filthy homes and dirty dorm rooms, but it’s not nearly that simple. So, what is the deal with bedbugs, and more importantly, how do you deal with them if you have them? Good questions. Let’s start from the beginning.</p>
<p><br> <strong>What are bedbugs? </strong></p>
<p><br> Belonging to the Cimicidae family, bedbugs are small, wingless insects that feed on blood (read: they’re parasites). While several species of bedbugs exist, there are two in particular that prefer human blood: Cimex lectularius (typically found in temperate regions) and Cimex hemipterus (found in tropical regions). Both species are stealthy.</p>
<p><br> Their modus operandi is the sneak attack—the “dine and dash,” if you will. It takes bedbugs only a few minutes to feed on a human, and they promptly retreat to their hiding places (beds, couches, walls, any place strategically close to their food source) when they’re full. To make matters worse, bedbugs are nocturnal creatures, preferring to eat before sunrise, so their “victims” are usually sleeping during the whole ordeal.</p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/sustainable-tourism-it-s-not-just-for-tree-huggers-go-local-and-laundry-free-with-beantown-bedding</id>
    <published>2018-09-15T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-08T12:20:25-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/sustainable-tourism-it-s-not-just-for-tree-huggers-go-local-and-laundry-free-with-beantown-bedding"/>
    <title>Sustainable Tourism: It’s Not Just for Tree-Huggers! Go Local and Laundry-Free with Beantown Bedding</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Sustainable-Bed-Sheets_1024x1024.png?v=1565281082" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<div>As the movement toward sustainable tourism, eco-tourism, and conscious tourism gains momentum, travelers are packing, trekking, eating and sleeping greener. In the process of making a difference through their travel, they're also developing a whole new vocabulary—popularizing terms like “leave no trace” and “pro-poor”. They're choosing public transportation or car sharing services, such as Lyft and Uber; gauging their water consumption with a water footprint calculator; and scouring the landscape for locally sourced foods. They’re using tools like<span> </span><a href="https://www.tripadvisor.com/GreenLeaders" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">TripAdvisor’s Green Leaders</a><span> </span>to find accommodations that meet their demands for environmental responsibility.</div>
<br>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>This new breed of traveler is less concerned with cinnamon rolls being part of the free breakfast than whether the coffee is fair trade. They’re looking more closely at the hotel’s carbon offsets or their yurt’s green certifications than they are at free wi-fi and extra pillows.</div><br>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div></div>
<div>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>Beantown Bedding is helping the effort. Our innovative Laundry-Free Linens® are eco-friendly, high-quality disposable sheets that may be used for days or weeks and simply discarded, recycled or composted instead of laundered. For travelers, it’s all about convenience and hygiene—without the guilt! Guests at vacation homes no longer have to wash sheets before leaving or bringing home dirty linens to wash. The best part? There are never any concerns about whether or not you're sleeping on clean sheets.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span>What makes laundry-free sheets an eco-friendly choice is its 100% Biobased® fabric, made with eco-award winning TENCEL®, complete compostability and resource conservation. Each load of laundry avoided can save approximately 40 gallons of water and 7 kilowatt-hours of energy. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span>With alarming reports of increased bug infestations and questionable cleanliness of lodging facilities, Laundry-Free Linens® are a comforting choice for travelers concerned with hygiene and health away from home. Our fabric’s unique fibers even help the sheets stay cleaner as they are more resistant to the growth of bacteria, mold and dust mites than cotton or synthetic fibers. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span>Despite Beantown Bedding's clever play on convenience, hygiene and sustainability, we also seek to bring awareness to our social mission. Sales of Laundry-Free Linens® allow us to support Camp Sunshine, a retreat for children with life-threatening illnesses and their families. </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span><em>Beantown Bedding’s bundled biodegradable sheet sets are currently available on the Beantown Beding website, Amazon, Bed Bath &amp; Beyond, The Grommet and at select Barnes &amp; Noble College Bookstores.</em></span></p>
</div>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/college-students-save-time-and-the-planet-by-living-laundry-free</id>
    <published>2018-08-20T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-08T12:14:04-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/college-students-save-time-and-the-planet-by-living-laundry-free"/>
    <title>College Students Save Time and the Planet by Living Laundry-Free</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/College-Students-Time_1024x1024.png?v=1565280734" style="margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p>This time of year college students fill the football stadiums, rush fraternities and sororities, and of course, study for exams—but they’re not hanging out in the laundry room!</p>
<p> </p>
<p>No one knows this better than Beantown Bedding Co-Founders Joan Ripple and Kirsten Lambert, two moms who learned that most college kids get a failing grade when it comes to washing their bed sheets. Their solution? Laundry-Free Linens®...biodegradable bed sheets that can be composted or discarded instead of laundered.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>It's no secret that dorm room hygiene is elusive, with alarming reports of increased bed bug infestations, viruses and allergen levels, not to mention the characteristic dorm room odor. Beantown Bedding helps make it easier for students to have a healthy sleeping environment, and the added convenience factor of eliminating loads of laundry has even greater appeal for time-starved students. Laundry-Free Linens® offers a convenient alternative when there’s just no time for washing sheets. And since the average student washes sheets once a month or less, parents appreciate the prospect of a cleaner bed.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Beantown Bedding's Laundry-Free Linens® are a whole new concept in bedding. They look and feel much like conventional sheets and are noted for being incredibly soft. Since they're 100% compostable and biodegradable, these sheets can be used for days or weeks and simply discarded or composted instead of washed. As campuses step up their sustainability efforts, students will also take note that Beantown Bedding linens are made from renewable resources with eco-award winning TENCEL™ fiber. They're also USDA certified as 100% Biobased® and save more water (approximately 40 gallons per load) and energy (enough kilowatts per load to supply a light bulb for 2.5 days) than regular laundering.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>The Campus Connection </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>When Beantown Bedding first launched its Laundry-Free Linens®, the company conducted product testing with students from 22 universities nationwide, including Notre Dame, University of California and Boston University. The testing had great results. Students reported that the sheets were “amazingly comfortable”, and loved the fact that the linens made their bed feel “very clean” and that they could “just throw them away” instead of having to do laundry. In addition, Beantown Bedding was selected to participate in Stanford University’s Global Entrepreneurial Marketing program and worked closely with a team of graduate students and their professors on research and branding.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Today, you'll find Laundry-Free Linens® at various university hosted conferences and events, Airbnbs, overnight camps, day spas, hospitality venues, healthcare facilities and much more. Independent research conducted by a university program tested Laundry-Free Linens® against linen service sheets over a four-week period, and Beantown Bedding outperformed the linen service sheets in every category. In fact, Laundry-Free Linens® were preferred by 64% of participants for comfort and feel.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In dormitories and beyond, the response to Beantown Bedding has been overwhelmingly positive. It's no surprise to Co-Founders Kirsten and Joan. "Anything that makes life easier and cleaner in an environmentally friendly way is sure to be a hit," says Joan. “And leave it to college students to think outside the box,” adds Kirsten. During product testing, students dreamed up a number of creative alternative uses for Beantown bedding's Laundry Free Linens®—and the ideas go far beyong the proverbial toga party. This fall, expect to see less action than ever in the campus laundry room as students learn to Rethink Laundry.</p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/students-sleep-and-disposable-sheets</id>
    <published>2018-07-25T11:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-08T12:08:08-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/students-sleep-and-disposable-sheets"/>
    <title>Students, Sleep and Disposable Sheets</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p style="text-align: center;"><em><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Disposable-Sheets-College_1024x1024.png?v=1565280372" style="display: block; float: none; margin-top: 30px; margin-bottom: 50px;"></em></p>
<p><em>A version of this article originally appeared on Wonkhe, a blog and think tank focused on Higher Education.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p>How do sleep patterns impact students’ academic studies? A University Registrar recently looked into this topic when he began to study the phenomenon known as “social jet lag”. "</p>
<p> </p>
<p>[Researchers] Schirmer and Smarr analyzed two years of Northeastern student data and determined that a majority of students experience a misalignment between their natural internal rhythms and their school environment, known as social jet lag (SJL). In an academic setting, that could be a student whose internal timing is that of a night owl, but who has to wake up early twice a week for an 8 a.m. class. The study—the largest survey of real-world student SJL ever published—concluded that more SJL correlated to poorer academic performance (which, unfortunately, appears relevant for most students)."</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The recommendations here, notes the Registrar, are that universities should consider students’ sleeping and waking cycles when scheduling classes, and that students should also look at their own patterns of activity when choosing classes as well.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>“Students need to be cognizant of how they partition their time,” says Schirmer. “It’s really important for students to think about the timing of their activities to try to optimize their educational efforts. If your only time to study is midnight to 2 a.m., there might be some academic costs.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Notes Smarr: “Staying up late in college doesn’t make you a party animal or lazy student. Circadian clocks get later in puberty, and so people in their teens and early 20s tend to be more owlish. What we see here is that in a large, diverse population, when class times don’t accommodate that lateness, the quality of the education suffers, and this impacts the majority of students at the university.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Given that most students are ‘owlish’, the suggestion is that classes should, on the whole, start and conclude later in the day. This would generally improve the overall quality of education as fewer students would suffer from social jet lag.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Another way to enhance the sleep cycle for students is with Beantown Bedding, a range of disposable bed sheets. Beantown Bedding's “laundry-Free linens®” are biodegradable and compostable and are meant to be thrown away after just a few weeks.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Kirsten Lambert and Joan Ripple got the idea for throwaway bedding when they sent their children off to college and learned they rarely took the time to wash their sheets. Beds are like super-sized petri dishes for fungi, bacteria, pollen, soil, dust, and all sorts of detritus from the human body, according to Philip Tierno, a microbiologist and pathologist at the New York University School of Medicine. While it's recommended that you wash your sheets about once a week, that’s more than a tad unlikely for today’s busy students, so simply throwing them out looks like an interesting option. Beantown Bedding’s linens are made out of Tencel, a fiber made from organic compounds found in eucalyptus, which is soft, breathable, and less prone to wrinkles than cotton... 👍</p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/compost-communicator-member-spotlight-beantown-bedding</id>
    <published>2018-07-10T11:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:31:58-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/compost-communicator-member-spotlight-beantown-bedding"/>
    <title>Compost Communicator | Member Spotlight: Beantown Bedding</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Compostable-Bedding_1024x1024.png?v=1565279335" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></div>
<p><em> A version of this article originally appeared in the USCC Fall Compost Communicator. </em></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Compost Communicator recently sat down with the co-founders of Beantown Bedding, a U.S. Composting Council member who joined the USCC to learn more about ensuring that their product, Laundry-Free Linens®, is entirely compostable in the compost manufacturing world. Beantown Bedding has been exploring its products’ impact on fellow USCC members’ facilities.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Q. Tell us about the mission of your company in your market. </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Beantown Bedding developed compostable bed linens: eco-friendly disposable sheets that are soft and durable enough for weeks of use and are created with the intent of composting. The USDA certified 100% biobased product is chemical-free and made with eco-award winning TENCEL® fiber from eucalyptus trees. Laundry-Free Linens® are an innovative and convenient way for businesses and consumers to have clean sheets without the hassles of laundry.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Q. What are challenges to being a successful company in this industry? Are there ways that being involved in USCC is helping you meet those challenges? </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>As with any new product, it takes time to generate awareness. Some composting facilities are reluctant to accept unknown products. The USCC has been instrumental in providing networking opportunities that have led to partnerships and increased acceptance of our compostable bedding at some facilities across the country, such as WeCare Organics.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Q. What are some of the features that USCC offers that you find most useful? </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>We use the Compost Locator Map to help our customers inquire at composting facilities in their area. The educational resources, such as articles and fact sheets, are also beneficial to us and to our customers.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Q. If you could sit down with a compost manufacturing company to discuss any issue, what would it be and why? </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>A compost manufacturing company could offer valuable perspective on how to fast-track adoption of composting practices by businesses and consumers and develop the supporting infrastructure from the back end. There is no shortage of research or documentation of best practices to study, but implementation remains a challenge. Solutions require input from stakeholders at every stage of the process. In addition, we need to inspire development of new compostable products by removing barriers such as expensive testing and certification fees, which can be prohibitive to entrepreneurs.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Q. What do you think is a key element to the successful future of the compostable products in the U.S.? </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Innovation. We need new and creative ways to make composting a more accessible and compelling option. Several high impact companies from MassChallenge are doing this.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><strong>Q. Introduce your fellow USCC members to your team! What do you do to build company spirit? </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Beantown Bedding’s founders, Joan Ripple and Kirsten Lambert, are two momrepreneurs who came up with the concept of compostable bed linens when they searched for an easier way for their kids in college to have clean sheets. It turns out that their solution had broader appeal. Laundry-Free Linens® have been adopted by universities, hospitality businesses, healthcare and emergency management organizations nationwide. The company also won the bid to supply sheets for the Special Olympics World Games in Los Angeles.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><em><strong>The U.S. Composting Council (USCC)</strong> is involved in research, training, public education, composting and compost standards, expansion of compost markets and the enlistment of public support. The USCC provides support for generators of organic residues, compost producers, policy-makers, regulators, professionals and product users for the purposes of advancing the industry. Learn more: www.compostingcouncil.org</em></p>
<p><em> </em></p>
<p><em><strong>Beantown Bedding</strong> is a woman-owned Boston-based business recognized for its innovation by INDA (Visionary Award Finalist), MassChallenge (Global Alum), Babson Breakaway Challenge (Finalist), the Primetime Emmy Awards (celebrity gift bags) and Women &amp; Wealth's Magazine "17 Women to Watch in 2017". Learn more: www.beantownbedding.com</em></p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/twas-the-night-before-camp-a-moms-take-on-packing-for-summer-camp</id>
    <published>2018-05-01T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:32:54-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/twas-the-night-before-camp-a-moms-take-on-packing-for-summer-camp"/>
    <title>&apos;Twas the Night Before Camp: A Mom&apos;s Take on Packing for Summer Camp</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<br>
<p style="text-align: center;">Joan Ripple, Co-Founder of Beantown Bedding, recounts packing up her kids for summer camp -- and the certain items she doesn't want to see return home.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Camp-Sheets-Poem_1024x1024.png?v=1565278532" alt="" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p> </p>
<p style="text-align: center;">Beantown Bedding's eco-friendly disposable bed sheets are the perfect choice for summer camp! (Because who really wants those sheets back after camp?) Get a set today!</p>
<hr>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/free-emergency-supply-checklist</id>
    <published>2018-02-10T18:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:31:15-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/free-emergency-supply-checklist"/>
    <title>Free Emergency Supply Checklist</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<br><p><span>Our Emergency Supply Checklist covers a few essentials to have on hand in order to rapidly respond to unexpected disasters. Beantown Bedding's disposable sheets have been assisting Emergency Management professionals throughout the U.S. and they’ve become an integral part of emergency shelters across the country</span><span>.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><a href="https://gallery.mailchimp.com/79c678e8ff7c30464c033bd26/files/f06060cc-e9db-4dc1-847b-5ea90a1a487d/Emergency_Management_Checklist.pdf" target="_blank" title="Free Emergency Supply Checklist" rel="noopener noreferrer"><img alt="Free Emergency Supply Checklist" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Emergency_Management_Checklist_1024x1024.png?v=1564437210" style="margin-top: 50px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></a></p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: left;"><span>Disasters don't sleep. Beantown Bedding's eco-friendly disposable bed sheets are the perfect choice for your Emergency Planning needs.</span></p>
<p style="text-align: left;"> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/beantown-bedding-can-play-a-big-part-in-living-an-organic-life</id>
    <published>2018-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:30:52-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/beantown-bedding-can-play-a-big-part-in-living-an-organic-life"/>
    <title>Beantown Bedding Can Play a Big Part in Living an Organic Life</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Healthy Travel" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Healthy-Travel_1024x1024.jpg?v=1564437037" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><span>Beantown Bedding’s innovative bed sheets recently caught the attention of </span><em>Organic Life</em><span> magazine. In the publication’s fall feature, the health and wellness site got to know the backstory behind the company’s disposable bed sheets and learned more about the linens’ eco-friendly elements.</span><span> </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>With the average person spending about a third of their life in bed, it’s important to know what you’re sleeping on. But when you consider that standard bed sheets can require up to three pounds of chemicals to be made, the idea of slipping into all-natural, chemical-free sheets quickly gains appeal. Tencel, the botanic component behind Beantown Bedding’s Laundry-Free Linens®, is a premium fiber made from eucalyptus. While some sheets currently on the market can also be made with Tencel, those sheets are often woven and knit. As a result, they’re treated with extensive chemicals. </p>
<p><span><br>Not so with Beantown Bedding. <br><br>Beantown Bedding’s linens are hypoallergenic and they’re bound together with high-pressure water jets without colors, chemicals or unnatural finishes. Adding to their eco-friendliness, Tencel also requires 70% less land to produce and about 20 times less water to grow than cotton. (Water is also conserved on the back end as the linens are never laundered.)<br><br>“Conventional, non-organic cotton is grown and harvested using heavy quantities of chemical fertilizers, pesticides and herbicides in order to maximize efficiency and output,” notes Beantown Bedding Co-Founder Kirsten Lambert. “But Beantown Bedding has no chemicals at all.”<br><br>While Beantown Bedding was originally conceived with college students in mind, the brand has become a staple in the hospitality industry with hotels, Airbnbs, overnight conferences and events, and even day spas purchasing the product in bulk. “Businesses like these do such a large amount of laundry. When it comes to labor and loss and sustainability, we cut out about half of the operational steps." <br><br>Kirsten also notes that in hotels about a quarter of linens are lost, stolen, or damaged—a term referred to as shrinkage—which has helped spark even greater demand for Beantown Bedding within the hospitality sector.<br><br>Beantown Bedding’s linens are entirely compostable and many customers have found unique ways to recycle their disposable sheets after use. One university grinds theirs up in a wood chipper to be used as lawn cover during tailgates and some even mix the sheets with lawn clippings and mulch before composting.<br><br>Not only does using eco-friendly disposable sheets eliminate the water, energy, carbon emissions, detergent runoff, and supplies required to launder an entire business’s linens each day, it also minimizes the need and cost of manpower normally required to do that laundry—and in review-driven industries like hotels and Airbnbs, owners can ensure that bed sheets are clean, new and consistent for every guest.<br><br>Learn more about <a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/beantown-bedding-for-business">Beantown Bedding for your business here</a>, or pick up a set for yourself. Here’s to living Laundry-Free!</span></p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/sustainable-green-bedding-joins-fight-against-infectious-diseases</id>
    <published>2018-01-20T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:31:06-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/sustainable-green-bedding-joins-fight-against-infectious-diseases"/>
    <title>Sustainable, Green Bedding Joins Fight Against Infectious Diseases</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Disposable Sheets for Healthcare" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Disposable-Sheets-for-Healthcare_1024x1024.jpg?v=1564436606" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><span>When Joan Ripple and Kirsten Lambert started Beantown Bedding, fighting infectious diseases was the last thing on their minds. But recent world health emergencies and the resulting guidelines from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), have the co-founders thinking differently about their company's role in fighting deadly infectious diseases.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>"We began making Laundry-Free Linens® as a way to keep our kids healthy and their beds clean while they were away at college," explained Ripple. "With these new guidelines announced by the CDC, we realized that our product offered real benefits in the fight against deadly diseases."</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Some of CDC's new guidelines aim to eliminate the risk of potential infection through the environment. For example, these guidelines urge hospitals and other healthcare providers caring for Ebola patients to treat all potentially contaminated linens as regulated medical waste. This means instead of laundering, these linens are incinerated at temperatures in excess of 2,000 degrees.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>"When we started hearing about some of these infectious diseases, the light bulb went off for us," said Lambert. "Our products are designed to be disposable, and incinerating a product that is already designed to be disposable makes good sense."</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Beantown Bedding's products are an attractive alternative for healthcare organizations worldwide because of their easy disposal benefits. Beantown Bedding's Laundry-Free Linens® are made using an environmentally friendly fabric called TENCEL®, which can deteriorate in just two weeks in situations where the linens can be discard or composted instead of incinerated. Chemical-free, dye-free, and odor-free, Beantown Bedding products are also hypoallergenic, resisting mold, bacteria, and dust mites.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>"Beantown Bedding's eco-disposable sheets provide a convenient, comfortable and eco-friendly alternative to laundering," explained Lambert. "There are times, and circumstances, when doing laundry just doesn't make sense."</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/the-bosscast-meet-joan-ripple-and-kirsten-lambert-of-beantown-bedding</id>
    <published>2018-01-10T00:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:31:12-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/the-bosscast-meet-joan-ripple-and-kirsten-lambert-of-beantown-bedding"/>
    <title>The Bosscast: Meet Joan Ripple and Kirsten Lambert of Beantown Bedding</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Founders of Beantown Bedding" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Founders-Beantown-Bedding_1024x1024.png?v=1564435994" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><em>This interview originally aired as part of The Bosscast: Career Podcast in January 2018.</em></p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><em><strong>Q. Our listeners are busy trying to rise in their careers I’m sure they could all use a break from doing their laundry... tell me how your laundry free linens work?</strong></em></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>They’re certainly an option for anyone who is busy, but as a convenient disposable product with a great sustainability story, they have been particularly popular with college students (who rarely take the time to wash their sheets, we offer weekly/monthly subscriptions online so they come automatically), summer campers (Moms don’t want those sheets back anyway!), travelers that don’t trust cleanliness of sheets<span>—</span>whether it’s a luxury hotel or an Airbnb. They're also great for vacation home hosts like Airbnbs and VRBOs since doing laundry is like a second full time job for them, vacation home renters who have to bring their own sheets and Millennials who have created the “on-demand" economy.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong><em>Q. How did you two come up with the idea for Beantown Bedding?</em></strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>We love answering this question since everyone seems to be able to relate to the answer.  We sent our kids to college at the same time and realized they were too busy to wash their dirty sheets.  We decided to send them disposable sheets but there were no options for sheets that were disposable, comfortable and could be discarded in an eco friendly manner.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong><em>Q. You’re both mothers of college children, what have you learned about millennials and what they want?</em></strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Millennials are driving the on demand economy where they want what they want when they want it.  It’s all about convenience. Hence the rise and success of brands like Uber, Airbnb, Warby Parker, Casper Mattress, Dollar Shave Club, Blue Apron).  Laundry free linens® is a product that is right up their alley, they’d rather be taking a cooking class or going to the gym instead of washing sheets.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong><em>Q. Neither of you have a background in this business, but you had successful careers before. Can you talk about the transition from established careers to something completely brand new and learning about plants and linens to create a superior product?</em> </strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Actually, we both have business backgrounds, but not in textiles.  Through more than a year of just research, we learned about eco friendly plant fibers in non-wovens and reached out to the producers of those fibers to help us source a non-woven manufacturer.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong><em>Q. Your business is online based. You and your product have been on the today show and the view. Can you tell us how business is going and what has it been like being female entrepreneurs working in this space and any advice for your women out there listening?</em> </strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>Although our retail business is online, currently most of our time and resources are dedicated to the wholesale side of the business where we sell in large volume to the hospitality market.  Our main customers are universities for their summer programs and camps and the concept is so well liked that we now have multi year contracts with schools all over the country.  With respect to being female entrepreneurs…we couldn’t have asked for a better place than Boston.  There is a lot of support in the startup community here. </p>
<ul>
<li>In 2013, we were selected for MassChallenge, a global accelerator in Boston, and that program opened doors for us.  </li>
<li>There is no shortage of organized events and networking opportunities in the Boston area-some are exclusive to women and others are open to all entrepreneurs/startups. </li>
<li>There are thought leaders on the subject of female entrepreneurship such as the Center for Women’s Entrepreneurial Leadership right here at Babson College</li>
<li>There’s so much out there you could literally start by googling Female Startups in Boston.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><em>Q. I started this podcast thinking about the #MeToo movement and Women supporting other women, Women my age and younger looking for mentors. What do you do to support and help women who young entrepreneurs (or young women starting a podcast)? </em></span> </strong></p>
<p> </p>
<p>This past year we had a tiny bit of breathing room which allowed us to start giving back to the community. </p>
<ul>
<li>We were Alumni in Residence for MassChallenge which meant we were mentors to the 2017 class of entrepreneurs.  Many of the female founders came to us for advice specifically because we were females in what has traditionally been a male dominated environment. </li>
<li>Outside of the MC women’s network, we have been able to use our own network of contacts to help young female entrepreneurs make valuable connections,</li>
<li>We have supported female college students through internships</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong><em>Q. </em><em>All work and no fun isn’t good for anyone. What do you do to unwind? How do you maintain relationships with friends and loved ones in a 24/7 buildings world?</em></strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>We literally schedule personal time on our calendars and try to stick to it. It seems to work pretty well.  Occasionally, I’ll meet long-time friends for breakfast,  take a mindfulness class and even work on plans to renovate<span> </span>my 300 year old home. Kirsten makes fitness a priority and loves hiking and walking her dog at the beach.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong><em>Q. How do the two of you work together successfully and remain friends?</em> </strong></span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>I think we continue to amaze ourselves on this topic, but it all comes down to trust and the fact that we are each willing to be flexible.  We also realize that if we come to a standstill on important decisions, the Company would suffer—no one benefits.  It’s also the fact that we each appreciate the sacrifices the other has made to grow the company, which keeps us good friends as well as business partners.</p> <br>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/the-ultimate-holiday-gift-for-travelers-campers-college-kids-and-more</id>
    <published>2017-12-15T17:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:30:46-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/the-ultimate-holiday-gift-for-travelers-campers-college-kids-and-more"/>
    <title>The Ultimate Holiday Gift For Travelers, Campers, College Kids and More!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Best Gift for Traverlers and More" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Best-Gift-for-Travelers_1024x1024.png?v=1564434998" style="float: none; margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px;"></p>
<p><span>Are you looking for a holiday gift for your favorite traveler, Airbnb host, camper or college student? Now there's a way to provide clean sheets without the laundry! Beantown Bedding's Laundry-Free Linens</span><span>®</span><span> are the first and only product of its kind, offering the comfort of washable sheets with the convenience of disposables. These biodegradable bed sheets may be used for days or weeks and simply discarded or composted instead of laundered. How's </span><em>that</em><span> for a gift that keeps on giving?</span></p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Beantown Bedding was<span> </span><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/about">founded by two momtrepreneurs</a><span> </span>after they sent their kids to college and learned that they rarely took the time to wash their sheets. But offering a convenient, comfortable and compostable alternative to laundering has turned out to have even broader appeal beyond college campuses. Laundry-Free Linens<span>®</span><span> </span>have seen tremendous growth in the hospitality and healthcare industries as well as with camps and overnight conferences and events. The innovative product has created<span> </span><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/press">quite a buzz</a><span> </span>with features on <span>The View and The Today Show and</span> inclusion in the Emmy Awards celebrity gift bags. People are <span>fascinated by the concept and often</span> surprised by the comfort, with one travel blogger simply summing it up as “epic!”</p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;">Laundry-Free Linens® and Beantown Cares</span></h3>
<p>Beantown Bedding is truly a pioneer of disposable home textiles. The Boston-based startup has received national media attention for its clever play on convenience, hygiene and<span> </span><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/sustainability">sustainability</a>and its Laundry-Free Linens® represent an entirely new concept: luxury disposable linens. After days or weeks of use they may simply be discarded or composted instead of laundered.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>A member of the U.S. Green Chamber of Commerce, Beantown Bedding is also a proud alum of MassChallenge and is a former INDA Visionary Innovation Award finalist. The company's<span> </span><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/pages/we-give-a-sheet">Beantown Cares</a><span> </span>program seeks to make a social impact through its support for Camp Sunshine, a retreat for children with life-threatening illnesses and their families, and K.I.D.S./Fashion Delivers for U.S. service members abroad.</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>Where to Buy:</strong></span><span> </span>Laundry-Free Linens® sheets sets and pillowcases are currently available on the<span> </span><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/products/laundry-free-linens">Beantown Bedding website</a><span> </span>and on the websites of select retailers including Target, Bed Bath &amp; Beyond, The Grommet, Barnes &amp; Noble College Bookstores and various luxury boutiques.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/meet-the-boston-founders-taking-the-hospitality-industry-laundry-free-with-biodegradable-bed-sheets</id>
    <published>2017-11-25T17:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:31:53-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/meet-the-boston-founders-taking-the-hospitality-industry-laundry-free-with-biodegradable-bed-sheets"/>
    <title>Meet the Boston Founders Taking The Hospitality Industry Laundry-Free with Biodegradable Bed Sheets</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Founders Disposable Sheets" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Founders-College_1024x1024.png?v=1563915474" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p>When cofounders Kirsten Lambert and Joan Ripple each sent their children to college, they realized just how time-consuming washing your bed sheets can be. In fact, they found that most college students didn’t like the hassle and often avoided it. While on the search for disposable sheets, they happened upon a better idea: Beantown Bedding.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Lambert and Ripple created hypoallergenic, biodegradable sheets made from a botanic fiber from eucalyptus called TENCEL, making the disposal process eco-friendly. The sheets can be used for days or weeks and then discarded or composted, in replacement of laundering.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>The Boston-based duo originally brought their product to market focusing on college students, but has expanded to the hospitality industry in addition to general consumers. They said the product can benefit “college kids who are too busy to wash sheets, overnight campers whose moms don’t want those sheets back anyway, travelers who question the cleanliness of hotel sheets, Airbnb hosts who don’t want to do laundry constantly (and improve their turnover time), hosts that want their guests to know the sheets are brand new just for them (and get better reviews), and vacation property renters who would like to simply leave all the sheets behind.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In July, Beantown Bedding was featured on the nationally televised CNBC show “Power Pitch” where the entrepreneurs pitched to a panel of investors and market experts including Dominic Chu (Markets Reporter for CNBC), Kelly Trumpbour (Investor and Founder of See Jane Invest), Kelly Hoey (Author, Speaker and Investor) and Nir Lieberboim (Managing Partner of DGNL Ventures).</p>
<p> </p>
<p>They were also named among<span> </span><em>Women &amp; Wealth Magazine’s</em> "17 Women to Watch in 2017" and the startup’s innovative product has gained national media attention as a selection for the Emmy Awards celebrity gift bags and as favorite items on both “The View” and "The Today Show.”</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Beantown Bedding is also a 2013 alum of the prestigious MassChallenge accelerator, a 2014 INDA Visionary Award finalist, and a 2016 Babson Breakaway Challenge finalist. “Beantown Bedding is recognized as an innovator in today’s on-demand economy, helping the world live laundry-free with clean new sheets delivered whenever, wherever they’re needed,” Lambert said.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Now located nationwide on beantownbedding.com, target.com, bedbathandbeyond.com, and amazon.com, the company is also planning to expand into the healthcare and emergency management markets. Beantown Bedding also currently has a new bedding product in consumer testing.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In addition to all of this, Beantown Bedding gives back in a charitable way. Each time a Laundry-Free Linens<span>®</span><span> </span>subscription is purchased, a sheet set is donated to organizations that make a social impact. As Beantown Bedding continues to grow rapidly, the owners are hoping for potential partnerships with nationally recognized brands.</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/3-must-haves-for-every-vacation-rental</id>
    <published>2017-10-15T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:32:27-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/3-must-haves-for-every-vacation-rental"/>
    <title>3 Must-Haves for Every Vacation Rental</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Sheets for Vacation Homes" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Vacation_Home_Rental_1024x1024.jpeg?v=1563915091" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p><span>With the rise in popularity of home sharing sites like Airbnb and HomeAway, many people today are turning their vacation homes into vacation rentals. </span><span>While renting out your home has never been easier, there are a few necessities that can often be overlooked when it comes to preparing your place for a short- or long-term stay. If you keep the following three items stocked in your vacation rental, you’ll be sure to keep the five-star reviews rolling in.</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>1. Reliable Wi-Fi with an easy-to-enter password</strong></span></h3>
<p><span>When arriving in a new city, the first thing many people do is to search for the different amenities nearby. This can include restaurants, coffee shops, tourist attractions and local stores. When guests are coming from out of town (or even out of the country) access to the Internet is critical, and for many guests, time spent at your vacation rental might be their only chance to connect with friends and family or plan out their day. Without a reliable Wi-Fi connection, your guests are essentially stuck, and having to navigate a complicated Wi-Fi password can only make an uncertain situation worse.</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>2. Coffee, tea and a bowl of fruit</strong> </span></h3>
<p><span>Guests may arrive at your vacation rental late at night or even half-asleep from a long day of travel, which means they may face-plant straight into bed. But when they wake up the next morning, nothing makes a guest happier than discovering coffee, tea and fresh fruit to serve as a quick breakfast before heading out to explore. Even if your guests don’t arrive late at night, figuring out what to do about breakfast can often be overlooked. Having coffee, tea and fruit on hand is sure to earn you a favorable review with your guests. It's also unlikely that your short-term guests will polish off all that coffee and tea, meaning you can easily roll this treat over to your next group of guests and keep the five-star reviews coming!</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>3. Beantown Bedding Laundry-Free Linens®</strong> </span></h3>
<p><span>One of the most important things for guests staying in a vacation rental is that the property is clean, and at the very top of this list is having a clean place to sleep. Let your guests rest assured that their bed is as clean as can be with Beantown Bedding’s Laundry-Free Linens®. Our soft, clean and 100% compostable bed sheets assure your guests that they’re the </span>first<span> </span><em>and only</em><span> guests to be sleeping on a set of sheets. Guests can also be confident in knowing that they’re doing their part to help the environment, since Beantown Bedding's Laundry-Free Linens® are 100% biodegradable, compostable and hypoallergenic.</span><span> </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>An added bonus? As a vacation rental owner, Beantown Bedding means less work for you! Instead of spending countless hours washing bed sheets whenever your guests depart, s<span>tock up on Laundry-Free Linens® so </span>you can simply toss the sheets into the compost and put a new set on the bed. Give yourself a vacay from vacation rental laundry and<span> </span><a href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/products/laundry-free-linens">pick up some individual sets here</a>, or get a volume quote for your vacation rental business.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/target-goes-local-with-beantown-bedding-students-get-dorm-ready-with-disposable-sheets</id>
    <published>2017-08-31T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:32:57-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/target-goes-local-with-beantown-bedding-students-get-dorm-ready-with-disposable-sheets"/>
    <title>Target Goes Local with Beantown Bedding! Students Get Dorm-Ready with Disposable Sheets</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Beantown Bedding at Target" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/Target-Beantown_1024x1024.jpg?v=1563914784" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p>Beantown Bedding announced a new partnership with Target this week that will put its Laundry-Free Linens® on shelves for students—and with an estimated 150,000 college students set to return to Boston, the timing couldn’t be better.  It’s part of Target’s localization strategy to deliver a locally relevant, personalized experience for guests. Target’s CEO Brian Cornell explained the Boston Fenway store’s role in the new strategy to the Associated Press last year: “It's a great example of localized marketing…great local assortment of merchandise that tells our guests we understand we're in their hometown.”<span> </span></p>
<p> </p>
<p>“Since we developed Beantown Bedding specifically for busy college kids, we’re particularly thrilled to be a part of Target’s Back to College collection,” said Kirsten Lambert, CEO and Co-Founder of Beantown Bedding.  “College kids juggle a lot of things over the course of a semester, and have to choose between spending time in the laundry room or sleeping in dirty sheets.”  Laundry-Free Linens® can be used for weeks and are disposable, so students can have clean sheets without wasting time on laundry.</p>
<p> </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p><span>While convenience is clearly the key benefit, what makes the sheets truly innovative is that they’re both comfortable and compostable. Made with TENCEL®, an award winning eco friendly fiber from Eucalyptus, they’re hypoallergenic, USDA 100% Biobased and compostable; returning to nature in as little as two weeks.</span></p>
<p><span><br><br>According to the American Academy of Allergy, Asthma and Immunology, “Dorm life breeds mold, dust mites, bacteria and viruses.” Beantown Bedding Co-Founder Joan Ripple adds, “It’s no wonder college kids get sick and suffer from allergies. As mothers ourselves, we were concerned about their health and decided to come up with a solution.” As it turns out, Beantown Bedding’s “solution” has caught on well beyond the college campus. The company’s wholesale business is changing the way linens are handled in the travel and hospitality industry, offering a more efficient and sustainable alternative for conference centers, university housing, camps and Airbnbs across the country. In 2015, the company was chosen to provide bedding for the Special Olympics World Games in Los Angeles.</span></p>
<p><span><br><br>While Beantown Bedding’s innovative sheets are available online, this week marks the company’s first foray into Target stores, including five in the Boston area: Fenway, Framingham, South Bay, Somerville and Watertown.</span></p>
<p> </p>
<hr>
<p><strong><em><br>Beantown Bedding</em></strong><em> is </em><em>a woman-owned Boston-based business recognized for its innovation by INDA (Visionary Award Finalist), MassChallenge (Global Alum), Babson Breakaway Challenge (Finalist), the Primetime Emmy Awards (celebrity gift bags) and Women &amp; Wealth's Magazine "17 Women to Watch in 2017". Learn more: <a href="https://info.beantownbedding.com/e1t/c/*W7RR9Bp1WKZrfW7w4hW_70m7Lw0/*V1Q-_c7qxD0SW7L89P32phxX-0/5/f18dQhb0Sjvk8YXNsnW3YQQ0Y51FcdHN5s9DSvWrBCTW3MpzC43frrzVW5y5LkQ61TllDW8m1PM562SwhqW8r4KMf8tzLyDW5y5jh-1rfXlzW1kRpb77YD42jW67HG8d8r4B5xN5x4_rsRLgCPN7Ykg3JQJJn6W3Lqnm_8q5FTlW67Tp-x8m7Y9zN5wM1SsnK2DdW5L1yJ85FxwsVW5_N0_w5K_zXKW3lj2tv3blhRkW6gB-L733ys2nW3nmmWW5Fw3KPW39qCxT8h5xSpW5RVkPr5pgdFfVQG48K3kldSjW5sFwDd5rQfBBW8Kqxm43dMHvWW8yVV6j8hJlrCVRz4bz8dzJ4dW8vZj168DPv5zW8FjsLB8h4BlDN3jLzNQR7nw3W3YVCyw5jd-0xW3gj2sh8fPzq0W5B-NMx42ktpLMPs031gkKmyW5qm0cv47w1MlN3ss32cSxSxKV215-p1Jp46lW9j2M3x6H4J_XW4N6WlN7s2nV3W29gbvM5y66nHN40ZB899XfwsM7s2GR16Ymmf3t_V4H03" data-saferedirecturl="https://www.google.com/url?hl=en&amp;q=http://info.beantownbedding.com/e1t/c/*W7RR9Bp1WKZrfW7w4hW_70m7Lw0/*V1Q-_c7qxD0SW7L89P32phxX-0/5/f18dQhb0Sjvk8YXNsnW3YQQ0Y51FcdHN5s9DSvWrBCTW3MpzC43frrzVW5y5LkQ61TllDW8m1PM562SwhqW8r4KMf8tzLyDW5y5jh-1rfXlzW1kRpb77YD42jW67HG8d8r4B5xN5x4_rsRLgCPN7Ykg3JQJJn6W3Lqnm_8q5FTlW67Tp-x8m7Y9zN5wM1SsnK2DdW5L1yJ85FxwsVW5_N0_w5K_zXKW3lj2tv3blhRkW6gB-L733ys2nW3nmmWW5Fw3KPW39qCxT8h5xSpW5RVkPr5pgdFfVQG48K3kldSjW5sFwDd5rQfBBW8Kqxm43dMHvWW8yVV6j8hJlrCVRz4bz8dzJ4dW8vZj168DPv5zW8FjsLB8h4BlDN3jLzNQR7nw3W3YVCyw5jd-0xW3gj2sh8fPzq0W5B-NMx42ktpLMPs031gkKmyW5qm0cv47w1MlN3ss32cSxSxKV215-p1Jp46lW9j2M3x6H4J_XW4N6WlN7s2nV3W29gbvM5y66nHN40ZB899XfwsM7s2GR16Ymmf3t_V4H03&amp;source=gmail&amp;ust=1528540033985000&amp;usg=AFQjCNHWFt9RDUL-1vXwH5QzuOlRtyGaDA">www.beantownbedding.com</a></em></p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/4-dorm-room-essentials-to-save-you-time</id>
    <published>2017-08-30T00:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2020-06-12T03:32:01-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.beantownbedding.com/blogs/beanstalk/4-dorm-room-essentials-to-save-you-time"/>
    <title>4 Dorm Room Essentials to Save You Time</title>
    <author>
      <name>Beantown Bedding</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="text-align: center;"><img alt="Back to College" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/1634/4037/files/back-to-college_1024x1024.jpg?v=1563914425" style="margin-top: 20px; margin-bottom: 50px; float: none;"></p>
<p>It’s indeed that time of year again! For many college students, returning to school is full of excitement. And if you’re embarking on your freshman year? Even better! This is <em>your</em> time to head out of the house and into the world!</p>
<p> </p>
<p><span>College is a new chapter filled with different people, countless things to learn and experiences that will shape you for the rest of your life. But what’s lacking in college? Plenty of spare time! Lucky for you, Beantown Bedding has you covered with our list of <strong>Dorm Room Essentials to Save You Time</strong>. Don’t let the start of a busy semester get the better of you. When you’re away from home, a few tricks and time savers can make a very big difference in the dorm.</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>1. Hand-Held Steamer</strong></span></h3>
<p><span>If you’re headed to a school event, an interview, a class presentation or if you simply need to look your best, chances are your clothes need to look their best too! This makes having a hand-held personal steamer a leading dorm room essential. Time is of the essence when you’re away from home and opportunity costs are high. Who wants to be ironing clothes in their dorm room when they could be grabbing a bite with friends before the big event? Stock up a steamer today.</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>2. Extra-Long Tech Chargers</strong> </span></h3>
<p><span>Outlets can be hard to come by in your dorm (especially when we all have multiple devices to charge every night), so extra-long phone and computer chargers can seriously come in handy. These allow you to charge your devices from across the room and <em>still</em> keep your laptop and cell phone at your fingertips. Start each day recharged and fully ready to take on the ultimate college trifecta: sleep, school work and friends!</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>3. Stainless Steel Water Bottle</strong> </span></h3>
<p><span>Not every dorm will have a vending machine, or will even have easy access to a dining hall, but most dorms <em>do</em> have a water fountain. Come prepared for dorm life with a stainless steel water bottle that keeps your water cold for hours on end. (P.S. Double-walled bottles are the way to go!)</span></p>
<h3><span style="color: #6aa84f;"><strong>4. Beantown Bedding</strong> </span></h3>
<p><span>This list wouldn’t be complete of course without the ultimate back-to-college, time-saving, eco-friendly item: Beantown Bedding’s Laundry-Free Linens®! These 100% compostable bed sheets are a great solution for dorm living where finding time to do your wash—<em>or even finding an open machine in the laundry room</em>—can be incredibly difficult. Beantown Bedding’s fully compostable bed sheets allow you to sleep clean without the hassles of laundry. Simply toss or compost the sheets and put on a new set. It’s a genius way to experience every minute of college life and still live the Laundry-Free lifestyle! Stock up on a set today.</span></p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
